# JASMINE TERRY FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

# **SUMMARY**

Full-stack web engineer well-prepared to transition related education and hands-on projects to excel in an entry-level developer role. Focused on learning, innovation, and purpose-driven work. Prior experience in positions of leadership, service, and industrial work has helped develop communication, collaboration, and management skills necessary to succeed in a team environment.

# CONTACT

**■** jasmine.terry91@gmail.com **③** jasmineterry.now.sh **⑦** Fanwood, New Jersey **in** jasmineterry92 **⑤** JTCode2408

# **SKILLS**

FRONT END	BACK END	GENERAL
HTML	NodeJS	Git/version control
CSS	Express	Slack
Styled Components	Knex	Command Line
ReactJS	SQLite3	REST API
JavaScript	SQL	Docker
Reactstrap	DB Design	Cypress
LESS		Jest
Material UI		Python
Typescript		

### **EMPLOYMENT**

Lambda School · Remote

Student Team Lead · Mar. 2020 to Current

Mentored 8-10 students in problem solving, effective learning, and agile development environments

Led 1:1 code reviews, team standups, and provided daily technical support via Slack and Zoom

Provided supplemental education and resources on various topics related to web development

Lifestation Medical Alert · Union, NJ Product Specialist · Jan. 2017 to Sept. 2019

Updated software, troubleshooted, restored and tested medical alert devices

Innovated new regulations and processes for product specialist position Solely responsible for the updating and troubleshooting of over 100 devices daily

Assisted in other warehouse operations such as shipping, refurbishing, data entry, and processing returned devices into company system

Target · Norfolk, Virginia

Team Member · Feb. 2014 to May 2016

Led instocks team and trained new team members on policies and procedures

Cross trained and supported multiple teams such as instocks, backroom, and salesfloor

Provided exceptional customer service, displayed ability to quickly solve problems and work under pressure

# **PROJECTS**

Story Squad Mar. 2020 to May 2020

Story Squad is a web 'gaming' application to encourage reading, and writing for children grades 3-6

Built using ReactJS, Typescript, TypeORM, and Material UI, and incorporating data science

Collaborated with other Lambda students as part of a team of 5 full stack developers, working with a stakeholder over 7 weeks on ongoing project Contributed to creating dashboard and match-up pages for child users, as well as increasing code climate score on both front and back end from a F to an A

Deployed Link

Spotify Song Suggester Jan

Jan. 2020 to Jan. 2020

One week cross-functional student team built a mock Spotify feature web application

 $\label{eq:Built using ReactJS} \textbf{Built using ReactJS}, \textbf{Redux}, \textbf{Styled Components}, \textbf{NodeJS}, \textbf{Express},$ 

Knex, and incorporating data science

Individual contribution on front end team of 3 developers, specifically registration, recommended songs and dashboard components Deployed Link

Game Of Life Nov. 2019 to Dec. 2019

'Conway's Game Of Life' original adaptation

Built using ReactJS, CSS, and Styled Components

Solely responsible for adopting rules based on Conway's original Game Of Life, application styling, and deployment

Utilized React hooks and Immer dependency for state changes of cells, CSS to implement grid feature, and Styled Components for main styling Deployed Link

## **EDUCATION**

Lambda School · Oct. 2019 to Current Full Stack Web Development & Computer Science Remote

SAE Institute · Jan. 2011 to Oct. 2011 Audio Engineering Diploma NYC, NY

# **ACTIVITIES**

**Internship** Audio Engineering

Worked closely with head engineer/owner on audio recording projects.

Recorded and mixed songs for clients.

Maintained business/client relationships.